# Giovanny González Baltazar



#### About

125B 298, San Nicolás del Sur. Mérida, Yucatán. 97285 México

giovanny.gonzalez.19@g
mail.com

9991454542

gggiovanny.github.io/cv/

giovanny-gonzalezbaltazar

gggiovanny

Programming languages

Javascript SQL Python PHP C# Kotlin Java C/C++ HTML/CSS

#### Frameworks

React (Javascript)

Codeigniter (PHP)

Laravel (PHP)

FastAPI (Python)

Android Jetpack (Kotlin)

#### Soft skills

Analytical skills

Detail-oriented

Critical thinking

Integrity Leadership

Research

Stress management

Business vision

Written and oral communication

#### Languages

Spanish (Native) English (B2)

### Summary

Bachelor in Computer Systems Engineer from the Instituto Tecnológico de Mérida, with almost 3 years of professional experience at the same time of studying. Giovanny has worked in small, but highly coordinated teams developing massive web products as well as custom web-based solutions for national level franchises. Proficient in many languages and frameworks (such as React and FastAPI), and experienced in Typescript, SQL, Git, PHP and agile methodologies. He has proven to be very versatile, being able to work in both backend and frontend; and with a quick adaptation to new languages, frameworks and tools, as well as an assimilation of the culture and good practices of each team where he has worked.

#### Experience

#### **Boy Scouts of America**

08/2021 - Present

React Developer

Currently, he works as frontend React developer using agile methodologies with CI/CD in the multidisciplinary team in charge of the Event Registration System for Boy Scouts of America.

- · Convert stories in to new features using React/Typescript/Redux/RxJS/Styled Components
- Communicate with users when it is needed in order to solve specific issues
- Always keep in sync with the design and backend teams
- Keep the codebase maintainable be keeping it modular and self-documented
- Write tests using React Testing Library and Jest
- Document processes and 'tribal knowledge' in Confluence

### The Ksquare Group

07/2021 - Present

Fullstack Developer

He works as a nearshore developer, currently for The Boy Scouts of America. His main goal is to deliver a high-quality result in a timely manner, following the Ksquare culture.

#### **Génesis Aplicaciones**

01/2020 - 07/2021

Junior Web Developer

He was in charge of developing and maintaining some massive web products, the main one being the TimbraXML billing web application. Besides gaining a lot of knowledge of frontend and backend web development, he learned what is a good workflow among a professional development team, supported by version control tools, progression boards and effective communication channels.

- Migrate, develop and maintain the TimbraXML billing web application
- Deliver custom web-based solutions (PHP/CodeIgniter/JQuery) for national level franchises
- Turn core processes into documented libraries with modern and readable syntax
- Make flows with Git to avoid crashes between teammate's changes

## **Grupo Dicas** 06/2019 - 12/2019

Technical Support Assistant

Originally tasked to be an assistant in technical support and server administration, he ended up doing all the engineering process to develop an Android application.

- Gather and interpret information about the experience of using software by users with little or no computer knowledge
- Used modern software design architectures (MVVM and observer pattern)
- · Reverse engineer an existing system to integrate it to another with zero documentation
- Implemented a REST API with PHP and Laravel
- Secured the requests with JSON Web Tokens

#### Systems development trainee

06/2018 - 08/2018

Marbol Industria Mueblera

Temporal member of the development team and mentored by Felix Amaya Valencia, from whom he quickly gained recognition and was assigned tasks of the same weight as those given to permanent members of the team. Working there, he learned to understand the importance of knowing the problems in depth before writing even a single line of code.

- Design modules of the internal custom ERP system with C# Windows Forms.
- Create the backend for my modules using T-SQL tables and stored procedures.

#### Education

## Instituto Tecnológico de Mérida

03/2019 - Present

Scouts de México · https://scouts.org.mx/

Jefe de Tropa (YUC1990357)

Awards

#### HackSureste 2018

Team MeseBot

Awarded third place for creating a high-impact innovation project. It consists of a system to deliver restaurant orders directly from the diner table to the kitchen through voice commands.

Publications

**Costeapp** 01/2020

Side project

An offline-first Web application (React, RXDB, react-hook-form, Bulma) for costing estimations of cooking recipes.

## Asset validation application

01/2019

Grupo Dicas

An android application (Kotlin, Jetpack) to validate the existence of fixed assets with a QR code.

Fiestas Mexicanas 01/2018

School project

A Windows Forms (C#, .NET) desktop application for quoting, order management and piñata production.